Linh Chi Nguyen, PhD.

OVERVIEW

As an R&D developer, I have a diverse skill set with a decade of experience developing software in Linux and 7 years of expertise in functional programming. I am self-taught in computer science fundamentals and can handle full-stack tasks. At the same time, I keep my academic research interest in evolutionary game theory and self educate about artificial intelligence and have joined machine learning projects as an AI/ML engineer. My background in finance and economics also enables me in data science tasks. Usually I approach work with a theoretical mindset, then integrate real-world business requirements to develop practical applications, with necessary tools.

I can relocate but can also work remotely. Here is my linkedin, github, and stackoverflow. Contact me at +84 (385) 136 193 and chinguyen.dev@gmail.com.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelance Developer Dec 2020 - present

Tech stack: Ruby on Rails, JS, Python, React, etc

- Projects in Python: use cycleGAN to translate photo to Monet on huggingface; mixing tests, grading tests with computer vision (openCV), save the grades to SQLite database, and build a test bank (storer).
- Projects in JS, React, Nodejs: neural net scoring yoga pose in browser; online shop REST API with MongoDB; admin dashboard

R&D Developer - Dinh Vi Bach Khoa - Haiphong

July 2020 - December 2020

Tech stack: C# .NET + Angular + SQL

• Attend regular briefings. Develop financial app issuing electronic billing abiding with the updated regulation (Circular 133). Communicate with clients and partners (from Japan, UK) regarding satellite contract. Small team hence work closely with the CTO and others.

Backend Developer - Taledo GmbH - Berlin

Feb 2020 - April 2020

Tech stack: Docker + Ruby on Rails + Postgresql

• Shadow Screening call and Candidate Qualification call with Talent Manager, Account Manager. Agile development with Bitbucket and Jira. Bugfix the platform, admin area + candidate area + recruiter area. Feature building: email notification, filtering candidate.. Refactoring, working with database (writing query, running migration)

Data Scientist / Software Developer - creditshelf AG - Frankfurt Tech stack: Java + Ruby on Rails

May 2019 - December 2019

- As Data Scientist: Team up with Data Team and Java devs to automate credit rating tools. I bridge in the domain knowledge from my degree (finance banking) to test the code base so that it exports financial reports and an in-house credit rating. Those information aids the data-driven decision of lending.
- As Software Developer: Develop a CRM, particularly in charge of optimizing the state machines: the credit project, loan, and loan part state machines. Proposed a deep neural network approach. Manipulate SQL database
- I learn to take agile development, version control and CI/CD seriously.

EDUCATION

PнD in Economics, University of Trento

2015 - 2018

Scholarship holder.

Thesis: Society in Simulation. Cooperation and Bargaining behaviors.

Programming language: Scheme/Racket

- I simulate a population of agents playing the classic games of Prisoner's Dilemma (cooperation game) and Nash-Demand (bargaining game). I let the population evolve in a survival of the fittest way, and we see emerging strategies that sustain cooperation / equitable share norm in our society.
- Tutor work for Joint European Master of Local Development UNITN

Intensive C summer bootcamp - 42 Paris coding school

2018

Programming language: C: piscine

• Assignments: Build a simple LISP interpreter, build up string libraries from the ground, etc.

MSc in Economics, University of Trento.

2013 - 2015

Merit Award 1200 euro.

Advisor: Prof Luciano Andreozzi

Thesis: Evolution of behavior in the repeated Nash Demand Game. A computer simulation

Programming language: Mathematica, Matlab, R, Python

BS in Advanced Program in Banking Finance, Hanoi National Economics University.

2008-2012

Advisor: Prof Nhuong Bui Huy

Thesis: Fuzzy method in MA evaluation and strategic partner choosing in banking sector in Vietnam

Awarded third prize in "Students Doing Research" competition.

PUBLICATIONS & CONFERENCES

• Publication of thesis preliminary result on EAI: 600+ downloads, cited by 4.

GAMES CONGRESS - Maastrict

2016

Speaker: Evolution of behavior in the repeated Nash Demand Game. A simulation

RACKETCON - St Louis, USA

2016

Granted & Speaker: Simulation of population playing the Prisoner's Dilemma game in Racket

SCIENCE OF CHOICE workshop and summer school - Max Planck Institute of Demographic

Granted & Speaker: Youtube.

2015

SKILLS

Linux10 yearsEnglishB2ItalianA2GermanA1

Vietnamese Mother tounge